Hello, and welcome to Lesson 35
你好，欢迎来到第35课
of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
的这个微积分导论与Wolfram U。
The topic for this lesson is L’Hospital’s rule.
本节课的课题是L'医院的规则。
Let’s being with a brief overview of the lesson.
让我们随着对本课的简单概述。
Let’s say you have a continuous function like x^2
假设你有一个连续函数，如x^2。
and I ask you to find the limit as x approaches 5.
我请你找出x接近5时的极限。
What you could simply do is to plug in the value 5
你可以简单地做的是插入值5
in the function expression and you’ll get back the correct answer,
在函数表达式中，你会得到正确的答案。
which is of course 25 in this case.
在这种情况下，当然是25。
But if the function has a point discontinuity,
但如果函数有一个点不连续。
then this would not work.
那么，这将无法工作。
For example, over here for g, there is an issue at 1
例如，在这里，对于g，有一个问题在1
because the denominator becomes 0.
因为分母变成了0。
If you try and find the value at 1,
如果你试着在1处找到这个值。
then you get back an indeterminate answer.
然后你会得到一个不确定的答案。
Now of course in this case, what you could do is
当然，在这种情况下，你可以做的是
to simplify the function algebraically like I’ve done over here,
就像我在这里做的那样，将函数代数化。
and then things work just fine.
然后事情就好办了。
If I now plug in x = 1,
如果我现在插入x=1。
I get back the limit of the function g when x goes to 1.
当x为1时，我取回函数g的极限。
But there are functions for which this will not work.
但有些功能是无法使用的。
For example, you have h over here, which is Log[x – 1]/(x – 2),
例如，你有h在这里，这是Log[x - 1]/(x - 2)。
and simplifying h makes no difference.
和简化h没有区别。
The question is what do you do in such a case?
问题是在这种情况下，你该怎么办？
In such a case, you can apply something called L’Hospital’s rule,
在这种情况下，你可以应用一种叫做L'Hospital规则的东西。
and that is the theme for this lesson, L’Hospital’s rule.
这就是本课的主题，L'Hospital的规则。
Okay. Before going on to the rule itself,
好吧，在谈规则本身之前。
let’s talk about so-called indeterminate forms.
我们来谈谈所谓的不确定形式。
Let’s say you have a function f which is Sin[x] and g which is x.
假设你有一个函数f是Sin[x]，g是x。
Now you try and work out the ratio f[0]/g[0],
现在你试着计算出比值f[0]/g[0]。
and you get back an indeterminate.
而你得到的却是一个不确定的结果。
That’s an indeterminacy of the form 0/0
这就是0/0形式的不确定性。
because both the values are 0 at 0.
因为在0时，两个值都是0。
If you take the function h over here, then that’s (2x – 1)/(3x + 2),
如果你把函数h放在这边，那么就是(2x-1)/(3x+2)。
and if you plug in x = ∞, you get back something like ∞/∞,
如果你插入x=∞，你会得到类似∞/∞的东西。
so that’s again an indeterminacy.
所以这又是一个不确定因素。
Next if we take the function y over here,
接下来如果我们把函数y放在这边。
then at 0 you have a 0 times ∞ over here,
那么在0的时候，你这里有一个0倍的∞。
so that’s an indeterminacy of the type 0 times ∞.
所以这就是0乘以∞的不确定型。
When you try and evaluate it, you get back indeterminate.
当你试着去评价它时，得到的却是不确定的结果。
Finally if you take the function z—that’s Csc[x] – Cot[x]—
最后如果取函数z--那就是Csc[x]--Cot[x]--。
and again at 0, you have ∞ – ∞.
又在0时，你有∞-∞。
That’s a problem.
这是个问题。
When you try and evaluate it, you get back indeterminate.
当你试着去评价它时，得到的却是不确定的结果。
The point is that you will have situations in which
关键是，你会遇到以下情况
the system gives you back indeterminate,
系统给你回不确定的。
and then the question is how do you find limits in such cases?
然后问题是，在这种情况下如何找到极限？
As I said earlier on, the way to do that
就像我前面说的，方法是这样的
is to find the limits using L’Hospital’s rule.
是用L'Hospital规则找极限。
L’Hospital’s rule says that if you have a ratio f[x]/g[x]
L'Hospital的规则说，如果你的比例f[x]/g[x]。
and you want to work out the value of that limit as x approaches a,
当x接近a时，您要计算出该极限的值。
then what you do is you simply work out the limit of f'[x]/g'[x]
那么你要做的就是简单地计算出f'[x]/g'[x]的极限。
at that value a—assuming of course that that limit exists.
在该值a--当然，假设该限制存在。
You can reduce a problem to a problem of computing
你可以把一个问题简化为一个计算问题
the limit of a quotient of derivatives.
导数商的极限。
For example, in our function from the introduction,
例如，在我们从介绍的函数中。
you had Log[x – 1]/(x – 2) when x approaches 2,
当x接近2时，你有Log[x - 1]/(x - 2)。
and you see over here that when you actually take
你看这里，当你真正采取的。
the derivative and take the ratio of those two,
的导数，并取这两者的比值。
things are much better.
事情好多了。
You can plug in x = 2, and you get back the answer of 1.
你可以插入x=2，得到的答案是1。
You can confirm the answer with Limit,
你可以用Limit确认答案。
and you do get back the same result, 1.
而你确实得到了同样的结果，1。
L’Hospital’s rule is a very powerful rule which says
L'Hospital的规则是一个非常强大的规则，它说
if you need to find the value of the limit f[x]/g[x],
如果你需要找到极限值f[x]/g[x]。
you simply find the derivatives of the numerator
你只需找到分子的导数。
and denominator separately and then plug in the values if that works.
和分母分开，如果可以的话，再插上数值。
Okay. As an example of 0/0,
好吧，那就以0/0为例作为一个0/0的例子。
let’s go back to our ratio f[x]/g[x], Sin[x]/x.
让我们回到我们的比率f[x]/g[x]，Sin[x]/x。
Now you see over here that individually you have 0/0,
现在你看到这边，单独地你有0/0。
but then if you take derivatives, things get much better
但如果你做了衍生品，情况就会好很多
and you get back Cos[x], which has a nice value at 0,
然后得到Cos[x]，它在0处有一个不错的值。
namely, it has 1.
即它具有1。
The limit of f[x]/g[x], Sin[x]/x, is just 1.
f[x]/g[x]的极限，Sin[x]/x，只是1。
That’s a very nice and important result.
这是一个很好很重要的结果。
Okay. Next.
好吧，下一个。下一个
If you go on to ∞/∞ like with the function h,
如果你像函数h一样继续∞/∞。
then you have (2x – 1)/(3x + 2).
那么你有(2x-1)/(3x+2)。
You work out the limits, and they are both ∞.
你锻炼出的极限，他们都是∞。
But if you could take derivatives and take a quotient,
但如果你能拿衍生品去做一个商。
then you just get back 2/3,
那么你只要拿回2/3。
and so the limit of the function h is just 2/3.
所以函数h的极限只是2/3。
Next, go on to the type 0 * ∞ for the function y[x].
接下来，继续求函数y[x]的类型0*∞。
Now in this case you don’t really have f[x]/g[x],
现在在这种情况下，你并没有真正的f[x]/g[x]。
so you write it as e^(1/x)/(1/x) and take the derivatives.
所以你把它写成e^(1/x)/(1/x)并取导数。
Then if you plug in x = 0, you do get back the answer ∞ from above.
那么如果你插入x=0，你确实可以从上面得到答案∞。
That’s the limit for y at 0 from above.
这就是y在0处的极限，从上面看。
Here’s a plot which shows quite clearly that at 0,
这里有一张图，可以很清楚地看出，在0。
the function does approach ∞ if you go from the right,
如果你从右边走，函数确实接近∞。
if you go from above.
如果你从上面走。
Okay. On to ∞ – ∞ for the function z[x].
好吧，就说说∞-∞的函数&lt;i&gt;z&lt;/I&gt;[&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;]。在∞-∞的函数z[x]。
Now in this case, what you do is you first of all simplify.
现在这种情况下，你要做的就是首先要简化。
Write the cosecant as 1/Sin[x] and cotangent as Cos[x]/Sin[x]
将余割写成1/Sin[x]，余切写成Cos[x]/Sin[x]。
and get back a ratio.
并取回一个比率。
If you work out those two limits separately, you get back 0/0,
如果你把这两个极限分别计算出来，就会得到0/0。
but then if you work them out in terms of derivatives,
但如果你用导数来计算它们。
you get back Tan[x], which is just 0 at 0,
你得到的是Tan[x]，这只是0的0。
so the answer for the limit is just 0.
所以极限的答案只是0。
Okay. Now in some cases, you apply L’Hospital’s rule
好吧，现在在某些情况下在某些情况下，你会运用L'Hospital的规则。
more than once to get the answer.
多次得到答案。
For example, here’s a function f defined to be e^x/3x^2.
例如，这里的函数f定义为e^x/3x^2。
If we try and apply L’Hospital’s rule once at ∞,
如果我们试着在∞处应用一次L'Hospital的规则。
then you get back ∞/∞ again.
然后你又回到∞/∞。
That’s again indeterminate, so what you do is
这又是不确定的，所以你要做的是
you apply L’Hospital again, and now things look good
你再去申请L'Hospital，现在一切都好了
because you get back ∞/6, which is ∞,
因为你得到的回报是∞/6，也就是∞。
so the answer for the limit is ∞.
所以极限的答案是∞。
You can apply L’Hospital’s rule repeatedly,
你可以反复应用L'医院的规则。
but of course it’s going to be more time-consuming
但当然，这将是比较耗时的
and more expensive to do so.
且成本较高。
Okay. Now some more indeterminate forms.
好了，现在再来一些不确定的形式。现在再来一些不确定的形式。
We have ∞^0 to begin with.
我们有∞^0开始。
Here’s an example.
这里有一个例子。
Let’s say we have x^(1/x).
假设我们有x^(1/x)。
If you plug in x goes to ∞, you get ∞^0, so that’s an indeterminacy.
如果你插上x去∞，就会得到∞^0，所以这是一个不确定因素。
What you do in this case is you apply a logarithm,
在这种情况下，你要做的是应用对数。
and when you do that, then you get back
当你这样做，那么你就会得到回
something which is going to be much more tractable
易如反掌的东西
because the law of logarithms says this is Log[x]/x.
因为对数定律说这是Log[x]/x。
Then what you do is you plug in the derivatives over here,
然后你要做的就是把衍生品插在这里。
and you get back 1/x.
而你得到的回报是1/x。
When x approaches ∞, the answer is just 0, so Log[y] = 0,
当x接近∞时，答案刚好是0，所以Log[y]=0。
which says that the limit is going to be just 1.
其中说，极限要只有1。
That’s a plot of the function
那是函数的曲线图
showing you it approaches 1 as x approaches ∞.
当x接近∞时，显示它接近1。
As another example, let’s take 0^0.
再举个例子，我们以0^0为例。
When you take x^x and apply 0 to it, you get back 0^0,
当你把x^x应用于它时，你会得到0^0。
but then again, you think of it as being a logarithmic case,
但你又认为这是一个对数的情况。
so apply logarithms and you get back xLog[x] like over here.
所以应用对数，你会得到xLog[x]，就像这里一样。
Then write that as Log[x]/(1/x), apply L’Hospital
然后写成Log[x]/(1/x)，应用L'Hospital
and you get back that when x = 0, the answer is 0,
而你得到的结果是，当x=0时，答案是0。
so the original limit is just going to be e^0 = 1.
所以原来的极限只是要e^0=1。
Finally, let’s take the case where you’ve got 1^∞.
最后，我们来看看你有1^∞的情况。
When you’re at π/2, this function becomes 1—Sin[π/2] is 1—
当你在π/2时，这个函数就变成了1-Sin[π/2]是1-。
raised to Tan[π/2] is ∞, so that’s 1^∞.
提高到Tan[π/2]是∞，所以是1^∞。
Again, you need to to some logarithmic work.
同样，你需要做一些对数工作。
You say let’s take logarithms.
你说我们就拿对数来说吧。
You get Log[Sin[x]^Tan[x]].
你得到Log[Sin[x]^Tan[x]]。
Pull down the Tan[x]—it’s a power—then apply L’Hospital like before.
拉下Tan[x]--这是一种力量--然后像之前一样应用L'Hospital。
You plug in π/2, and things look better.
你插上π/2，事情就好办了。
The answer is 0 for the logarithm, and so the actual limit is 1.
答案是对数为0，所以实际极限为1。
Okay. That brings me to the end of this lesson.
好了，我的课到此结束。本课到此结束。
Basically L’Hospital’s rule is very useful
基本上L'Hospital的规则是非常有用的。
when you have indeterminate forms of the type,
当你有不确定的类型形式时。
let’s say, 0/0 and ∞/∞.
比方说，0/0和∞/∞。
But of course if you’ve got something like 0^∞ or other things,
不过当然如果你有0^∞之类的东西。
you can work too.
你也可以工作。
Let’s say with some algebraic manipulation, you can tackle
比方说，通过一些代数操作，你可以解决以下问题
the case where you have 0 * ∞ and ∞ – ∞.
的情况下，你有0*∞和∞-∞。
If you take logarithms, then you can also tackle the cases
如果你采取对数，那么你也可以处理以下情况。
where you have ∞^0, 0^0 and 1^∞.
其中你有∞^0，0^0和1^∞。
Of course sometimes you need to apply L’Hospital’s rule
当然有时你需要运用L'Hospital的规则。
multiple times to arrive at a suitable answer.
多次得出一个合适的答案。
That’s the end of this lesson.
这节课就到此为止。
The next lesson will talk about slope fields and Euler’s method,
下节课将讲坡场和欧拉法。
but before we do that, do revise L’Hospital’s rule.
但在这之前，请修改L'医院的规则。
It’s a very important rule, a very useful rule,
这是一个非常重要的规则，一个非常有用的规则。
and you surely will benefit a lot from review.
你一定会从审查中受益匪浅。
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
我在这里停一下谢谢你了